bloomingdales.com 2007-12-18

# Bloomingdale's - Privacy Policy

|  | | | | | |   
---|---|---|---|---|---  
| 

|   

---  
  
At Bloomingdale's, we respect our customers and understand that you are concerned about privacy, so we've instituted policies intended to ensure that your personal information is handled safely and responsibly. We also have posted this privacy policy to let you know what kind of information we collect, how it is handled, with whom it may be shared, what choices you have regarding our use of your information and how you may access some of the data you provide to us. 

As we continue to develop our web site and take advantage of technologies to improve the services we provide, this policy likely will change. We therefore encourage you to refer to this policy on an ongoing basis so that you understand our current privacy policy. This policy last was updated on August 1, 2005. 

If you have any questions about this policy you can [click here](http://www1.bloomingdales.com/customerservice/index.jsp), contact us by phone at 1-888-529-2254 or write to:

Bloomingdale's Customer Service  
P.O. Box 8215  
Mason, OH 45040  

If you have any questions regarding your credit account(s) with Bloomingdale's.[Click Here](http://www1.bloomingdales.com/service/credit/index.ognc) for more information.

|  | 1| What information do we collect?  
---|---  
2| What are cookies and do we use them?  
3| How do we use your information?  
4| Do we share your information?  
5| What choices do I have regarding your use of my information?  
6| Is my information secure?  
7| Can I access my information?  
8| What about information about children?  
9| We want you to trust us  

We collect various types of information depending upon how you use our site.

  * When you order from us, we collect your name, address, e-mail address, phone number and credit card number (with expiration date) or gift card number. We also gather information on the person who will receive any gift you send (e.g., that person's name and address) and retain a record of your purchases. If you are a registered user and have signed in when you enter this information, it is automatically saved in your Address Book for your ease of reference.
  * At Checkout, we collect the above information, as well as a credit card number and a billing and shipping address. If you are a registered user and have signed in before entering that information, it will be automatically saved in your Wallet.
  * When you request to be on our mailing list (for e-mail or regular mail) or ask to receive the Bloomingdale's by Mail catalog, we collect your name, address, e-mail address and phone number. The information gathered will be shared with the Macy's, Inc. family of companies. We also may share this information with other third parties, including companies with which we have a relationship. At any time, you have the option to remove yourself from our mailing list, or to continue to receive promotional materials from us without having your information shared with third parties for marketing purposes. Please click here to see the choices you have regarding the use of your information.
  * We also gather information on the person who will receive any gift you send (e.g., that person's name and address) and we will retain a record of your purchases. If you are a registered user and have signed in when you enter this information, it is automatically saved in your Address Book for your ease of reference.
  * At Checkout, we collect the above information, as well as a credit card number and a billing and shipping address. If you are a registered user and have signed in before entering that information, it will be automatically saved in your Wallet.
  * When you register with us we also may ask for additional information (e.g., about your favorite brands and interests) in the section called My Profile, but you have the option not to provide it. We gather this information in order to offer services and promotions that may be of interest to you.

  * When you enter a sweepstakes or contest on-line, we usually collect your name, address, e-mail address and phone number. We also may ask you for additional information, such as your age, interests, product preferences or zip code.
  * When you submit a question to customer service, we need your e-mail address to respond, and you also may provide us with various types of information to allow us to answer your question.
  * When you apply for a Bloomingdale's credit card, we collect your name, address, email address, phone number, and other information needed to assess your credit worthiness and verify your identity, such as social security number and employer. We require this information to process your application. The personal information you provide is transmitted through a secure server using SSL encryption.
  * We may acquire customer lists from other parties so that we may invite new people to visit bloomingdales.com. Our policy is to acquire only lists of people who have indicated that they are willing to receive e-mail offers. Also, each time we send an e-mail offer, we provide people with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving future e-mail offers.
  * We also may receive some information about you from other sources and may add it to your account information. For example, we might get your updated address from a shipper or information on your preferences from another Web site conducting a promotion or event with us.
  * We have carefully selected a company, Coremetrics, to assist us in better understanding how people use our site. bloomingdales.com will place cookies on your computer to collect information. The information that is collected through these cookies tells us things like which search engine referred you, how you navigated around our site, what you browsed and purchased and what traffic is driven by banner ads and emails.

Coremetrics analyzes the information it collects from bloomingdales.com and returns it to us through a secure web connection. We use the information to help us understand your interests in our web site and how to better serve you. It also helps us provide you with more personalized product offerings. bloomingdales.com does not allow Coremetrics to collect credit card, username or password information.

Coremetrics may only use your personal information to perform services for us. It may not share your personal information with anyone else, or use it for any other purpose, except on an aggregate, non-personal basis (in other words, the information will not be identified with you). Coremetrics is required to maintain all of the information it collects and analyzes securely and in confidence. For more information on Coremetrics privacy policy, [click here.](http://www.coremetrics.com/company/privacy.html)

As a visitor to bloomingdales.com, you may choose to opt-out of Coremetrics' analysis of your browsing and purchasing behavior on our site. You may also choose to continue to benefit from the improved shopping experience that the Coremetrics analysis allows us to provide, but maintain your anonymity. To learn more about the various levels of privacy and confidentiality you can select with respect to Coremetrics on this site and to exercise your opt-out choices, click here.

Please note that Coremetrics collects data on our site using first-party data collection. As a result, blocking cookies served from third-party domains will **not** block these first-party bloomingdales.com cookies. You need to follow the opt-out process specified (see paragraph above) in order to opt-out of Coremetrics data collection. 

Back To Top  

A cookie is a small piece of information sent by a website that is saved on your hard disk by your computer's browser. It holds information a site may need to interact with you and personalize your experience. At bloomingdales.com, we use two kinds of cookies, session cookies and persistent cookies.

Session cookies exist only for as long as your browser remains open. Once you exit your browser, they go away. We use session cookies to maintain information we need to have in order for you to shop at bloomingdales.com. For example, the Session_ID cookie that we ask your browser to hold retains the ID for your shopping bag. Without the Session_ID cookie, you cannot add merchandise to your bag or make any purchases.

Persistent cookies, in contrast, last from visit to visit; they do not go away when you exit your browser. You can browse our site without accepting a persistent cookie. However, you cannot add merchandise to your bag or make any purchases. You may set your browser options to reject persistent cookies. Alternatively, you can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, which provides you with the opportunity to decide whether you want to accept it or not. In many instances, the "help" button on your browser tool bar will tell you how you can take these steps.

Cookies can be used by a web site to recognize you. But, that does not necessarily mean any personal information is stored in the cookies. At bloomingdales.com, we store no personal information about you in the cookies. Anything you choose to tell us about yourself as a registered user (like your address and e-mail address) is stored safely and separately on our secured servers.

Bloomingdales.com uses pixels, or transparent GIF files, to help manage online advertising. These GIF files are provided by our ad management and email service partners. These files enable them to recognize a unique cookie on your Web browser, which in turn enables us to learn which advertisements bring users to our website. The cookie was placed by us, or by another advertiser who works with these partners. The information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not contain your name, address, telephone number, or email address.

Back To Top  

We may use your information in a number of ways, including the following:

  * In order to serve you better, we may combine the information you provide us online, in our stores and through our catalogs. We use that information to improve your overall Bloomingdale's experience.
  * To improve the content on our website. For example, we may use cookies to find out which parts of our site or our products are visited most often. 
  * To enhance your online shopping experience. For example, we may use it to recognize you and welcome you to the site.
  * For marketing and promotional purposes. We send out e-mails and direct mail or catalogs to our customers about products or events that we think may be of interest to them. We also may send you offers for discounts or promotions, new arrivals or new site features. If you do not wish to receive e-mail from us, please click here to unsubscribe.

Back To Top  

The information gathered will be shared with the Macy's, Inc. family of companies. We also may share this information with other third parties, including companies with which we have a relationship. For example:

  * WeddingChannel (www.weddingchannel.com) operates the web site where you can access the Bloomingdale's bridal registry or register for your own wedding. When you use that website, both Bloomingdale's and WeddingChannel receive your information.[Click here](http://bloomingdales.weddingchannel.com/cgi-bin/gx.cgi/AppLogic+com.wc.Utility.NavBarForStaticHTML?frmSection=bloomingdales&location=%2Ftemplates%2FBloomingdales%2FHelpPages%2FPrivacyPolicyWC.html&storeGroup=BL) to see the Bloomingdale's WeddingChannel privacy policy.
  * bloomingdales.com may enter into a "co-branding" relationship with another website that offers you products or services (e.g., flowers). In those cases, you may link from bloomingdales.com to another site to purchase the item. In that case, both bloomingdales.com and the other web site may receive your information.
  * bloomingdales.com may team with a partner to conduct a sweepstakes or other event (e.g., a live web chat). In those cases, each of the participating web sites may collect or receive personal information from you. 
  * For some of our products, bloomingdales.com may provide you with a link to the supplier of that product so that you may get further information. If you link to the supplier's site, the supplier may collect or receive information about you according to its stated policy.
  * Like other companies, bloomingdales.com may use an outside company to place its advertising banners or links on other sites. In certain cases, the advertiser may collect information on people who click on the banner or link.

In most of the above situations, these third parties will receive your information because you will be visiting their web sites or using their links and, in doing so, you may provide information directly to them. You therefore should refer to their privacy policies to understand how they handle your information and what kinds of choices you have.

Bloomingdale's also may share your personal information with outside companies that perform services for Bloomingdale's. For example, we may retain an outside company to manage a database containing certain customer information or to create and distribute an e-mail offering. In those situations, the outside party is performing work for Bloomingdale's, and Bloomingdale's takes appropriate steps designed to ensure your information is used only to provide the services requested by Bloomingdale's, and not for other purposes.

Additionally, Bloomingdale's may share account or other information when we believe it is necessary to comply with the law or to protect our interests or property. This may include sharing information with other companies, lawyers or government agencies in connection with issues related to fraud or government subpoenas and warrants.

And in the event that some or all of the business assets of Bloomingdale's are sold or transferred, we generally would transfer the corresponding information about our customers.

Finally, Bloomingdale's may share your personal information with unrelated outside companies so that they can directly market their products or services to you if we feel that a company offers products or services that may be of interest to you. We also may provide you with the opportunity to sign-up on our web site to receive such e-mail offers.  

We provide you with a number of choices regarding our handling of your personal information online and offline.

Online your choices are:

If you do not want to receive e-mail from bloomingdales.com or do not want us to share your e-mail address and related personal information with unrelated third parties for marketing purposes, please follow the steps outlined below to submit a request electronically:

  * If you do not want to receive email, please use the [Contact Us](http://www1.bloomingdales.com/service/contact/index.jsp) Form and select the subject line "CUSTOMER SERVICE" from the drop down menu. In the message area, please type "UNSUBSCRIBE FROM EMAIL", along with the email address you want unsubscribed. (Please note that every time we send you an email, we will give you the option to unsubscribe from our e-mail list, so you'll be able to stop our e-mails at any time).
  * If you do not wish your e-mail address and related personal information to be shared with unrelated third parties for marketing purposes, please use the same [Contact Us](http://www1.bloomingdales.com/service/contact/index.jsp) form and select the subject line "CUSTOMER SERVICE" from the drop down menu. In the message area, please type "KEEP PRIVATE", along with your name and email address.
  * If you wish both steps to be taken, please use the [Contact Us](http://www1.bloomingdales.com/service/contact/index.jsp) form. Follow the same step as above, but type in the message area, "NO EMAIL/KEEP PRIVATE", along with your name and email address.

Offline your choices are:

If you prefer, you can contact us by phone at 1-888-529-2254, or write to:

BLOOMINGDALE'S CUSTOMER SERVICE  
P.O. Box 8215  
Mason, OH 45040

  * If you shop at our Bloomingdale's stores or through the Bloomingdale's By Mail catalog and wish to be removed from the list of customers that receive direct mail or from our telemarketing lists, please either: (i) write to Bloomingdale's Customer Service, P.O. Box 8215, Mason, OH 45040, or (ii) call Customer Service toll-free at 1-888-529-2254.

If you choose to write us, please include your name, address, phone number and Bloomingdale's credit card account number (if you have one), and state one of the following:

  * "NO MAIL OFFERS" (if you do not want to receive offers by mail)
  * "NO PHONE OFFERS" (if you do not want to receive offers by phone)
  * "NO PHONE OR MAIL OFFERS" (if you do not want to receive either).

Since customer lists often are prepared well in advance of an offering (sometimes 3-4 months before the offer is made), you may continue to receive some offers after you send us a request not to use your information for specified marketing purposes. We appreciate your patience and understanding in giving us time to carry out your request.

You also may use the address and phone number above to request that we not disclose your personal information to unrelated third parties for marketing purposes. If you choose to write to us, please include your name, address and Bloomingdale's credit card account number (if you have one) and state "NO THIRD PARTY SHARING" in your request.  

Bloomingdale's is committed to doing its best to maintain the security of information collected on its site. To try to prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place the appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

To the extent customer information is maintained, it is located on a secured server behind a firewall; it is not directly connected to the internet. The firewall meets recognized industry standards.

Encryption is a process by which a message or information is scrambled while it is in transit to bloomingdales.com. It is based on a key that has two different parts, public and private. The public part of the key is distributed to those with whom you want to communicate. The private part is for the recipient's use only. So long as you use a browser that allows for encryption, when you send personal information to us, you use a public key to encrypt your personal information. If your information is intercepted during the transmission, it is scrambled and very difficult to decrypt. Once we receive your encrypted personal information, we use the private part of our key to decode it.  

If you are a registered user of bloomingdales.com, you can update your information. 

If you would like to email our Customer Service Department please use the Contact Us Form and select the appropriate subject line from the drop down menu.

Questions regarding your charge account can be forwarded to our Credit Customer Service Department. Please use the Contact Us Form and select the appropriate subject line from the drop down menu.  

The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act took effect on April 21, 2000 and imposes certain requirements on websites directed toward children under 13 that collect information on those children, or on web sites that know they are collecting information on children under the age of 13. We want to let you know that it currently is bloomingdales.com's policy not to collect personal information on any person under 13. For this reason, our online sweepstakes are restricted to entrants who, at a minimum, are at least 13.

If this policy changes, Bloomingdale's will revise this portion of its privacy policy and will comply with the requirements of the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, which include providing notice and choice to each child's parent or guardian before collecting personal information.  

Your confidence in the bloomingdales.com shopping experience is our highest priority. If you have any concerns about privacy and security that have not been answered in the above policy, please [contact us](http://www1.bloomingdales.com/service/contact/index.jsp) and we'll do our best to answer your questions and put your mind at ease
